The rite is about to begin
เทศกาล Lantern Rite กำลังจะเริ่มแล้ว
Is the moon really gonna disappear?
ดวงจันทร์จะหายไปจริง ๆ เหรอ?
Got your lanterns ready, everyone?
ทุกคนเตรียมโคมของตัวเองพร้อมกันรึยัง?
All set!
เรียบร้อย!
Might be about time to put eyes to the sky. Wouldn't ya say, Tianquan?
ถึงเวลาที่ต้องแหงนมองฟ้าแล้วล่ะ ว่ามั้ย Tianquan?
Look!
ดูนั่นสิ!
When the sun's out, eat the sun. When the moon's out, eat the moon!
ยามตะวันทอแสงก็กลืนกินดวงตะวัน ยามจันทราทอแสงก็กลืนกินดวงจันทร์~
Whoa, is this the lunar eclipse?
ว้าว นี่คือจันทรุปราคาสินะ?
Under moon eternal, in radiant night, a maiden grants silk soft and light
ใต้จันทรานิรันดร์ ท่ามกลางราตรีเรืองรอง นารีประทานแพรไหม อ่อนนุ่มและเบาบาง
Under moon iridescent, in night divine, a maiden grants fiber for cloth so fine
ใต้จันทราล้อแสงรุ้ง ในราตรีศักดิ์สิทธิ์ นารีประทานเส้นใย สำหรับทอผ้าอันประณีต
For you
ฉันให้
Under moon of frost, in night so great, a maiden grants tools to divine our fate
ใต้จันทราเยียบเย็น ในราตรียิ่งใหญ่ นารีประทานเครื่องมือ เพื่อทำนายโชคชะตา
The fields are plowed, the seeds are sown, and from the earth, life is grown
จอบพลั่วไถพรวนพสุธา หว่านกล้าเมล็ดพันธุ์ ก่อเกิดชีวิตจากผืนดิน
The seedlings stretch, the crops do rise, and all unfolds before our eyes
ต้นกล้ายืดตัว พืชผลงอกงาม ทุกสิ่งพลันปรากฏสู่สายตา
Fruits are gathered, sweet wine is poured, these gifts we offer to our lord
เก็บเกี่ยวผลผลิต ไวน์หวานรินรด เป็นของขวัญนำถวายแด่ท่านผู้เป็นเจ้า
Pure as heaven, so fair and bright, she shines as light in this dark night
ผู้บริสุทธิ์เปี่ยมก้องสวรรค์ งามสง่าดั่งแสงเรืองรอง ส่องประกายดุจแสงในราตรีมืดมิด
And with her does this wish take flight
และเพราะนาง ความปรารถนานี้จึงโบยบินไป
Devoted soul, scattered and unbound
ครั้นอดีตเคยมีวิญญาณผู้ภักดี กระจัดกระจายไปทั่วทั้งบูรพาและประจิมดุจหงส์ที่โบยบิน
Let this lantern guide you home, by its light be found
ยามนี้ข้าจะจุดตะเกียงนำทาง เพื่อมิให้วิญญาณวีรบุรุษเหล่านั้นต้องหลงทางอีกต่อไป